All right, so so we do are ready for
some questions? Yes, sir. All right,
hello heroes. Yeah, thank you. Do you
think any of the Arab countries that
were struck will actually strike back or
will they count on the US and Israel to
do this for them? I'm wondering the
cultural dynamics playing into this
decision like losing face appearing weak
or being peaceful during Ramadan. The
Ramadan thing it's interesting to me,
too. Yeah, this is a big sin for this to
be launched during Ramadan. Mhm. Um
my UAE contacts told me yesterday that
um they sent their ships out of port
not to fight but just to protect them.
Uh we have not seen retaliation
uh from the Arab states yet and my guess
is we probably won't that they're going
to let the US and Israel do their thing
with some British air cover
and that's going to be it.
I agree with that completely. Uh Donkey
Man, do we think the war will last more
than a month? I think it will.
Yeah, you know, that's a great question.
Donald Trump said yesterday it's only
going to last a couple of days. He lives
in a fantasy world if he thinks this is
going to last a couple of days. Um I
wouldn't be surprised if there are
active US and Israeli hostilities for
weeks, but yeah, I could see this
lasting for a month, sure. I mean,
especially if um the Iranians bloody the
Israelis or our noses in some way that
we can't fathom, right? They They get a
missile gets through and I don't know,
blows up something that Israel or we
care about a lot and it and then there's
a domestic there's, you know, a domestic
concern that we can't just let it go.
That's right. Okay, um let's uh is Iran
actually causing damage anywhere even
with the numerous missiles fired?
Doesn't seem to do much. Is Iran hoping
for an off-ramp home still? Oh, I'm sure
they're hoping for an off-ramp. The
Israelis killed practically everybody.
It's not just the Ayatollah, his
daughter, son-in-law, and grandson.
It's It's the entire Iranian military
leadership was wiped out yesterday.
So [snorts] the the the second and third
string guys are in. Mhm. Yeah.
Um yeah. I mean so but is Iran actually
causing any damage anywhere is the
question. Oh.
Not that I've seen. I mean sure. Yeah. I
mean they they fired rockets at the
Jebel Ali the
the the free port in Dubai. They they
have
They've damaged Manama and Kuwait
airports. Uh they fired a rocket at the
Saudi oil fields that was intercepted. A
couple of hotels were were damaged in
Dubai.
There was
Yeah, one rocket landed in Abu Dhabi.
There's some damage but absolutely
nothing like what's being inflicted on
Iran. No no no question. It's definitely
a one-way street there when it comes to
that. Um but all they have to do is
survive. Um Diva Divya, do we think
hitting Dubai hard would be beneficial
for Iran right right now because of all
the American interests it's right now?
I think no and I'll tell you why because
that's where Iran does its business.
Iran I mean Dubai is chock-full of
Iranian businessmen and that's Iran's
outlet to the western world. That's how
Iran evades sanctions by having
businesses in Dubai. So I think no.
Hitting Dubai is not going to help Iran
at all.
John during during the
Iraq war, Bush and Cheney especially the
latter kept saying, "Oh, we're going to
have a cheap oil because of this."
Turned out it went exactly the opposite
way.
I I think I see a replay here. I think
the real damage is going to be economic.
I mean
high oil prices means high everything
prices. This is a president who's trying
to fight inflation more than anything
else, right? I mean that's the real risk
to him. That's right. That's exactly
right. And it's not like Venezuelan oil
is a panacea. It's not. It's filthy.
It's heavy. You have to inject it with
massive amounts of chemicals to clean it
up just to make it into home heating
oil. So, Venezuela is not going to be
the answer to our prayers. Oil prices
are going to go up. Uh Sasan, we get
such great questions. Um thank you. You
guys are great. Um what do you think is
the impact of the death of Khamenei on
the uh future of the regime in Iran? As
an Iranian, I'm worried yet another
extremist is chosen and the cycle
continues on and on. Love the show.
That, I think, is exactly what's going
to happen.
Absolutely 100% agree. That is exactly
what's going to happen. You know, and
the thing, too, is that
I think that in the West, we seriously
overestimated Ayatollah Khamenei's
authority. Mhm. Certainly, he was the
final word on on religious issues.
Certainly. But, you can take him out and
have literally nothing change. It's like
if you killed the Pope. Yes, exactly.
Exactly. No.
No, that's wonderful. I'm going to I'm
going to repeat that. Uh Mason uh oh uh
let's see. Reload. Um
Please reload. What are you doing? Okay,
good morning, gentlemen. The sneaky part
of my brain wondered how much of a
beating Iran will suffer before before
finally unleashing their hypersonic
missiles. I think they proved during
their probing strike on Iron Dome that
letting Israel and the US burn through
their limited arms supply that patience
is the best practice. Yeah, I mean, you
learn that when you have 7,000 years of
continuous culture, right? Also, why
does the American government always
imagine that killing a leader will end a
war?
>> I know, right?
>> Glad you mentioned the timeframe.
Germany fought beyond Hitler. If Trump
was killed today, nothing about our
country's day-to-day would change. And
somehow And somehow we expect other
countries to be different.
It's It's a childish mentality. The New
York Times just issued a push
notification saying that the Iranian
foreign minister says that a new supreme
leader will be chosen in the next day or
two.
So, there it is right there. Nothing
changes. It
You can take out the Pope and there's
just going to be another Pope. Yeah, if
you and I were in the Iranian leadership
or any leadership that was besieged like
this, we would say, "Oh, we have to
project continuity
in order to maintain domestic control."
I mean, they don't like the fact that
there have been protests and even if it
is just 300 people, you know, going
>> [laughter]
>> They don't like that. That's 300 too
many.
Um you know, regimes radicalize under in
times of war. That's
>> do. you know, that's just sort of
history. Um
you know, hypersonic missiles. We got,
you know,
Do they exist? Are they real? Oh, yeah.
They're real. The Russians have them.
The Chinese have them. The Iranians have
them.
>> The Iranians have them. That's what I
mean. Iranians have them. They exist.
So, so they're so they're they're So,
they Iranians keep are, you know, using
their usual florid language um as as
they do to say like, "Today is going to
be we're going to unleash our doomsday
scenario." Okay, maybe. But
Yeah. No, but the the danger of
hypersonic missiles is they'll go three
or four times the speed of sound. So,
you're you're dealing with a missile
going 2,500 mi an hour. You can't defend
against a missile going 2,500 mi an
hour. And so, maybe you can get it into,
you know, the Knesset building or you
can get it into the side of the USS
Abraham Lincoln or something like that.
And then, you know, the West is going to
have to deal with it. They don't have a
lot of them. They only have a couple of
them.
But, you know, we'll see if they use
>> them.
It's like the Afghan Mujahideen in the
'80s, right? They didn't have that many
Stingers, but they had to make them
count.
That's right, and they did. Um
Hello, gentlemen. Big fan. Wondering if
he thinks Iran's sleeper cells, if they
have, will be activated and if they will
be activated in the UK. In addition,
what will China's likely response be?
John, where do you get those lovely
sweaters like you wore on Diary of a CEO
from?
>> [laughter]
>> Let's dispose of the sleeper cells. Um,
they're they're probably they don't
exist, right?
Um, I don't think they exist in the US,
Canada.
>> Maybe. Maybe. Probably the UK, probably.
But they certainly exist in places like
Pakistan, India, Indonesia. Yeah,
they're out there. They're out there.
Um, and thank you for that. I I get
these sweaters at at Macy's. [laughter]
Oh, really? I thought you brought them
back from Greece or something. No.
Uh,
okay, China's response. Well, we already
China is doing what they always do. Um,
they're trying to be the adults in the
room. They keep saying, like, you guys
stop, respect Iran's sovereignty, just
stop. But that I think it's going to be
that's going to be about it. Ted, there
was a headline on The Onion a couple of
weeks ago that was funny because it was
so true. And the headline was, China
content to sit back and watch US destroy
itself.
And that's what we're going to see here.
No doubt. Um, how much leverage Jasper
wants to know does this give countries
like Russia and China to pursue their
military goals such as in Taiwan? I I'm
not convinced that that that China wants
to invade Taiwan. Uh, no. No, I don't
think so. If China wanted to invade
Taiwan, they would have done it two days
ago.
Yeah, that would have been the time. I I
am I'm I'm you and I, Ted, we're in the
minority of people who who believe that
China is not interested in invading
Taiwan. Yeah, we have. Um, and and the
Russians are very happy to see us
distracted and fighting the Iranians so
they can focus on the Ukrainians and not
have the American monkey on their backs.
Yeah. Now, I mean, I this it's
definitely look, uh, you know, when the
cat's away, it's always a good time. And
we're the cat. Um,
uh, Matt, I can remember Bob Baer
writing extensively about the Iranian
threat, specifically the ability to
covertly retaliate against the West and
shut down the Strait of Hormuz. Any
thoughts? It's been years since I read
his book. Memory is hazy, but I have a
feeling No, that that that memory is
correct. That's exactly what Bob Baer
wrote about. And uh and he was correct
then when he wrote that book 25 years
ago. He's correct today. Um the Iranians
can shut the Strait of Hormuz. If I were
the Iranian leader, I would shut the
Strait of Hormuz. Oh, I see.
They're not going to They're not going
to win a sustained bombing campaign, but
over the long term, you know, they live
there. It's their neighborhood, and they
can inflict real economic harm on the
West.
Um Ted and John thank Declan Brady. Love
the show. Welcome your unbiased opinions
and analysis. Why do you think Iran is
attacking its neighbors? Surely it's the
aggrieved party. Iran needs all the
support it can get. And how does hitting
Dubai and Kuwaiti airports help their
cause? Hope your comes through, John.
It's because there are There are two US
military bases in Kuwait. The
headquarters of the American Fifth Fleet
is in Bahrain. The world's largest US
Air Force base is in Qatar. Two US Army
bases are in
um
the Emirates. Uh there are multiple US
military, both Army and Air Force bases
in Saudi Arabia. So, there's no love of
Iran in these countries.
Well, exactly. I'm glad you you said
that there. I mean, I think I think
that's the final calculus, John. These
aren't their friends. They're not going
to get They're not going to become
friends. These are not any None of these
targeted countries are going to help the
Iranians in any way, shape, or form.
They're not even going to tweet on their
behalf. Absolutely not. Uh as someone
who served in the Navy, Amy Andy wants
to know, "This is very concerning for
me. Do you think we'll need to put boots
on the ground for this? Love you guys."
That right there is the $64,000
question.
So, everybody at the White House, the
Pentagon, and the State Department. And
all the talking heads from Capitol Hill
say that there will be no boots on the
ground. That would be the death knell
for the United States. If we were If we
had to put boots on the ground and fight
a country of 92 million people,
you know, I'm going to reiterate what
you said yesterday, Ted. And that is
that the US and Israel have to win. The
Iranians just have to survive. And that
is much, much easier than winning.
Yeah. Yeah. And they have the home field
advantage. Like Like let's not forget
that. Gonk, thank you for the Thanks for
the fiver. I'm intimidated. John looks
pissed. Rightfully so. World
>> I am, actually. I'm pissed about this.
World War
>> unnecessary war of war of choice.
Oh, I mean, it's one of the most
boneheaded and we've had a lot of
boneheaded wars. All of our wars are
boneheaded for the most part.
World War III not off the table?
I'd say never. Things can always spin
out of control. Yeah.
Um
Accident member for a month, thank you
so much. Is the only probable reason
Turkey hasn't been hit because of NATO?
If they're hit, it will trigger Article
5?
That's a good question, too.
Um
That is
That it could be. It could be that
the Iranians,
you know, have more important things to
worry about right now
than Turkey.
But sure, that could be it. And And
don't Don't forget Azerbaijan.
Right? There are Israeli There is an
Israeli base in Azerbaijan. The Israelis
have drones pre-positioned there. The
Azerbaijanis are or the Azeris are very
close to Turkey. So, I wouldn't at all
be surprised to see this expand to
Azerbaijan. Not at all.
Who's actually driving a
10 Australian dollars from Luminous?
Thank you very much.
>> Thank you. Who is actually driving Iran
policy in this administration? Is there
a coherent interagency process?
Or are with constant I I can answer
that. significant autonomy outside of
normal National Security Council
channels?
That's a great question. It's a It's
quite an important question. In a normal
situation, there are two bodies called
the Principals Committee and the
Deputies Committee. The Principals
Committee is chaired by the President,
and it includes the Secretary of State,
the Secretary of Defense, the National
Security Advisor,
the um Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of
Staff, and the Director of the CIA.
The Deputies Committee is the number
twos for all those people. It's chaired
by the Vice President.
Um
normally,
this policy would be coming out of the
the National Security Council.
In this odd scenario that we're in right
now,
Marco Rubio is both Secretary of State
and National Security Advisor.
And so, this is Marco Rubio's policy.
We We learned from the the this leak
from the White House last week that J.D.
Vance was opposed to an attack on Iran.
Tulsi Gabbard was opposed to an attack
on Iran, and the Chairman of the Joint
Chiefs came out and said that he was
opposed to an attack on Iran. Who does
that leave?
Marco Rubio. That's it. Marco Rubio is
running this policy.
Yeah, and Bibi Netanyahu. Um Bibi
Netanyahu.
Want to support the show with style? Go
to deprogram.live and check out our
merch. That's deprogram.live,
or check out the description below.
Thanks for watching. Um
What Big Question, why is the US
Israel's If you can summarize, I
would be grateful.
That's a It's a big good question. I
mean, we know it is. Yeah. Cuz the the
United States does anything and
everything the Israelis tell it to do
even when it's not in US interests to do
so.
Yeah. Um yeah, so I mean, why though is
the question?
>> And the the why is because of money and
politics. That's really what this comes
down to. You know, Citizens United made
it even worse so Miriam Adelson could
donate a hundred and fifty million
dollars to the RNC super PAC and AIPAC
can
just spend people out of office by
challenging them in primaries when they
do the slightest thing that the Israelis
don't like.
Israel is there's also other things,
right? Israel is a is a tech hub and the
United States feels like you know, that
that alliance with the intel that we get
from you know, from Israel is considered
valuable. But also we're
the the Israel the Israelis lobby.
They're spectacularly effective bullies.
They smear everybody. Like you criticize
Israel, you you know, you're slimed as
an anti-semite.
That's been their stick forever and up
until very recently it still worked.
It's finally you know, the spell is
broken but
I mean, there's more to it than that but
what do you think, John? Yeah, I think
that's it.
And and I think I think this may be
what breaks the spell. If the Israelis
suck us into
a war, a longer-term war rather than
just a few days of bombing, we're in
trouble and we're going to have to
seriously as a country reassess this
relationship. What do we get out of this
relationship? I understand exactly what
the Israelis get but what do we get out
of this relationship? By the way,
producer Trent is reminding me to
mention to everybody who's on YouTube
that if you go to membership and you
become a tier two member, you will be
thanked by us in the closing credits
of each and every show. So please go
ahead and do that. He's in the middle of
updating that list. I just wanted to
remind you of that.
Um will the
uh Bucktown crazy wants to know will the
US need to escort commerce ships through
the Strait of Hormuz?
Well, that's what Ronald Reagan did in
the 1980s when the Iranians threatened
to close the Strait of Hormuz. He sent
the US Navy there to escort each and
every oil tanker through the Strait. I
remember I remember being on a on a boat
in the Persian Gulf and seeing the the
SS Bridgeton. The Bridgeton was famous
in the '80s because the Iranians
attacked it and set it ablaze. It It was
the biggest oil tanker in the world at
the time. It ended up being towed into
port and repaired. It took a couple of
years to repair it. But, um
we may be headed into the same scenario
where there's going to have to be a
long-term heavy US naval presence in the
Gulf just to escort uh ships through the
Strait of Hormuz.
Um which of course could set us up for
being targeted. So, then, you know, it
it sets up it's a trigger for
escalation. Jacob, thanks for the 999.
Is it likely, John, that the CIA's
paramilitary is on the ground in Iran
already?
That's a great
>> That's a great question. I would say
probably not.
Now, granted, my my information is
dated, but
to have the CIA paramilitary on the
ground to carry out targeted killings,
the president would have to
um assert that a person is uh
what's called a clear and present danger
to the United States, to an American
installation,
um and to or to an American person.
And I I don't think we're there.
Can you Oh, this is good. Trevor House,
can you guys simply explain why you are
so against the attack. Do you agree that
Iran is extremely dangerous when left
alone? In a perfect world, what do you
think America's stance should be on
Iran? I'm really glad for this question.
John, why don't why don't you take it?
>> [snorts]
>> Uh
Iran
posed no threat to the United States.
None.
None. It had no nuclear weapon. It had
no nuclear weapons program. That was
confirmed twice by the CIA and by the
International Atomic Energy Agency.
>> And don't And didn't want one. And
didn't want one. And there was a fatwa
against developing one.
And even if they had one, they didn't
have a delivery system to to deliver it.
So, um
you know, why are we doing Israel's
dirty work for it? If the Israelis want
to attack Iran, then go ahead and attack
Iran.
But why did we have to do it? Why are
Americans dying
in the name of Israeli foreign policy?
More
uh $4.99 from Perez. Thank you so much.
And how about ironic to wage a war based
on nukes and take out the leader who
withheld a religious ruling against
nukes? Exactly right. You know, a a dear
friend of mine said yesterday that the
next Iranian grand ayatollah or or
supreme leader is just going to issue a
new fatwa revoking the old fatwa and
calling for a nuclear uh
uh weapons program.
Yeah, it's
Of course they will. I mean, you know,
you and I have been talking about this
for a long time.
Um okay, uh thanks for the 10 Australian
dollars. What's the current Israeli
assessment? Does Netanyahu's government
actually want a US invasion or do they
prefer Iran weakened with the regime
intact as a perpetual justification for
their own military posture? John, you
know
You know my answer to that.
>> Oh, yeah, yeah. No, I think that what
the Israelis want in Iran is what the
Israelis got in Libya. Chaos. They want
chaos. They want a civil war
and they want as many dead Iranians as
they possibly can get.
Um Isaac, thanks for the $5.
The US consulate was attacked in
Pakistan yesterday. I'm glad that came
up in response to the attacks on Iran.
Have we started a war with the Muslim
world?
Well, that's what we did last time.
Yeah. The answer's probably yes. Yeah.
We That is That's exactly what we did
last time. We killed 2 million Muslims
from, you know, 2001 to 2020. John, let
me ask you
Is this going to ex- I mean, many Arab
countries have a huge division between
the politics of their street, as they
say it, and the In other words, their
citizens and the policies of their
governments. Um
how much will this could could a schism
like blow up someone's government? Um
and it Where Where would you think they
would be most likely
If I were,
you know, the leader of Bahrain, I would
be genuinely worried today. If I were
the Pakistani government, I would be
genuinely worried today. If I were
You're always
He's always be worried. Yeah. But even
an Indian leader, I would be worried
about what my population in Kashmir
would be doing right now.
>> Yeah, they're They're already There's
massive protests in Kashmir cuz it's a
>> Massive. And the Saudis The Saudi royal
family, they've got to be
on the verge [music] of cracking down in
the Eastern province, which is almost
entirely Shia Muslim.